Michael Henry

he/him/his Boston, MA m.henry511@gmail.com https://aigyptios.github.io/ Empathetic front-end software engineer with over five years' experience building interactive JavaScript web applications. I have strong skills in modern, progressive web development with HTML5, CSS, Typescript, and React, a passion for writing clean and efficient code, an eye for user-centered design, excellent communication skills, and extensive experience working on Agile teams.

Experience

Software Engineer IIClarity Innovations

May 2020 - Present Boston, MA (Remote)

- Pair program to build a mission-critical military application in React, Typescript, GraphQL, Kotlin, Spring, and Postgres.
- Refactored legacy back end and APIs according to best practices; TDD, with tests in Jest, Enzyme, JUnit, and Cypress.
- Collaborate with UX designers, product managers, and software engineers to plan and execute application roadmap.

Software Engineer *Vivante Health*

February 2020 – March 2020 Athens, Greece; Boston, MA (Remote)

- Worked closely within Scrum team to add new features to customer-facing Angular 8, ngrx application, GIThrive.
- Interfaced with teams distributed between Athens, Greece and remotely throughout the United States.

Senior Front End Web Developer

Liberty Mutual Insurance

September 2017 – September 2018 Boston, MA

- Built Dojo 1 components for the customer-facing auto insurance sales application, tested with Jasmine and Selenium.
- Partnered with the in-house UX Design team for three months on UX research, persona creation, and iterative
 prototyping, turning mock-ups into interactive high-fidelity React and Redux applications used for live user testing.

Senior Interactive Developer

Publicis Sapient

July 2014 - September 2017 Boston, MA

- Spearheaded the development of a component-based design system in SCSS with an atomic design prototype tool (PHP).
- Built modular, responsive jQuery UI widgets for a wealth management analytics dashboard with D3.js visualizations.
- Single-handedly developed a large-scale dynamic spreadsheet component in Ember.js to be used across multiple work streams for a top-tier international financial services corporation in Boston.

Undergraduate Teaching Assistant

Computer Science Department, Boston College

September 2013 – May 2014 Chestnut Hill, MA

- Graded and reviewed materials 3 – 4 hours weekly for about 20 students per semester for two CS courses.

Education

Boston College (05/2014) GPA: 3.891/4, summa cum laude B.A. in Computer Science, Theology (Honors) Honors Program, Dean's List, Neuhauser Award in CS, Sophomore Scholar Award in CS

Aristotle University of Thessaloniki (09/2018 - 06/2019)

GPA: 9.13/10

School of Modern Greek Language, B2 Certificate Program

Skills

Code: JavaScript, Typescript, JSX, HTML5, CSS, SCSS, BEM, SMACSS, Node, Java, Kotlin, SQL, React, GraphQL, Jest, Enzyme, Cypress, Redux, Angular, git, JIRA, Gitlab, TDD, object-oriented programming, design systems, Material Design, data structures, algorithms, Agile

Languages:

Egyptian Arabic (basic, native bilingual) Greek (intermediate proficiency) French (basic) Spanish (basic)